A Guide to the Papers of the Proctor of the University of Virginia, (Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough), 1817-1828
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Proctor of the University of Virginia, 1817-1828 (Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough) 1817-1828
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-5/3
This collection consists of ca. 883 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This record group was recompiled from accessions MSS 2737 and MSS 3730
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains the papers of the first proctor Arthur S. Brockenbrough and his successors including Thomas H. Carter and Major Green Peyton. The earliest papers include 57 letters from Thomas Jefferson to Arthur S. Brockenbrough mainly concerning construction of the University buildings. The collection also includes an enclosure "A view of the whole expenses of the Funds of the University," [1821 September 30] copies of which were also sent to John H. Cocke and Joseph C. Cabell by Jefferson.
Among the correspondents are: Nelson Barksdale, A.H. Brooks, Joseph C. Cabell, John Hartwell Cocke, Joseph Coolidge, Gen. Henry A. S. Dearborn, Robley Dunglison, John Patten Emmet, Albert Gallatin, Alexander Garrett, John B. Gordon, Washington Irving, James Leitch, Dolley Madison, James Madison, Peter Maverick, Peter Minor, John Patterson, Bernard Peyton, Chapman Reynolds, Coleman Sellers, St. George Tucker.
The collection also contains a letter from Andrew Carnegie to President Edwin A. Alderman, 1905, and 15 medals and relics including Alderman's Phi Beta Kappa pin, a lock of George Washington's hair and the pen used by Andrew Jackson Montague to encorporate the Alumni Society in 1903.
A construction drawing of a detail of a modillion for the Rotunda by John Neilson, [ca. June/July 1825], was removed from this collection and filed in the Thomas Jefferson papers by date
Organization
The contents of the folders containing miscellaneous bills and receipts have been arranged chronologically in three groups: 1. full-sheet or half-sheet documents; 2. small items for which the versos are blank or only contain docketing that repeats information on the recto; 3. small items for which the versos contain docketing that differs from the information on the recto.
Contents List
- Albert Gallatin to D[abney]; C[arr] Terril [Terrell] 1817 July 7, ALS, 2 p. with address (Box-folder 1:1)
- Miscellaneous receipts 1817, ANS. 5 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
- J[ohn] Daingerfield to Nelson Barksdale 1818 February 26, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:3)
- St. G[eorge] Tucker to Nelson Barksdale 1818 April 15, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:4)
- W[illia]m Brent to Nelson Barksdale 1818 August 18, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:5)
- Miscellaneous receipts 1818, ANS. 21 items. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Jesse Lewis: account of with the Bursar, 1819 January 19 -, ADS.. (Box-folder 1:7)
- University of Virginia 1820 April 9, 4 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:)
- Isaac Collett: bill for "advertising for workmen to erect the Building... (in a Staunton paper)" 1819 March 18, ADS. 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:8)
- Survey of plot purchased from Jesse W. Garth for Central College, signed by Allen Dawson 1819 March 27, ADS. 1:00 PM. (Box-folder 1:9)
- James [W.] Widderfield to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [1819] March 27, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:10)
- Ambrose Flanagan to Nelson Barksdale 1819 April 1, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:11)
- List of items in Nelson Barksdale's account with the University that were lacking vouchers 1819 April 9, AD, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:12)
- Joseph Couden: bill for labor with receipt 1819 April 24, ADS. 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:13)
- Alex[ander] Garrett to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 MAY 12, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:14)
- James Leitch: account, with receipt 1819 May 13-1820 April 15, ADS. 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:15)
- Ja[me]s Leitch to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 May 14, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:16)
- Bramham & Jones: contract for supplies 1819 May 16, ADS. 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:17)
- Alex[ander] Garrett to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 May 17, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:18)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1696] 1819 May 17, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:19)
- Alex[ander] Garrett to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 May 24, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:20)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1698] 1819 May 28, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:21)
- P. A. Sabbaton to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 4, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:22)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1699] 1819 June 5, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:23)
- R[ichard] Ware to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 11, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:24)
- Joseph H. Smith to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 12, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:25)
- Curtis Carter and William B. Phil[l]ips: contract for bricklaying 1819 June 15, ADS. 3 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:26)
- W[illiam] Wood to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 15, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:27)
- Samuel Griscom to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 19, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:28)
- J[ames] Oldham to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 20, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:29)
- J[ohn]; H[artwell] Cocke to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 21, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:30)
- R[ichard] Ware to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 22, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:31)
- Jos[eph] H. Smith to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 June 24, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:32)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1706] 1819 June 27, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:33)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1708] 1819 June 29, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:34)
- Ja[me]s Dinsmore to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 July 2, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:35)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1711] 1819 July 2, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:36)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1717] 1819 July 14, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:37)
- R[ichard] Ware to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 July 22, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:38)
- Christopher Anthony to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 July 27, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:39)
- R[ichard] Ware to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 July 26, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:40)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1719] 1819 July 28, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:41)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1721] 1819 July 29, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:42)
- Alex[ander] Garrett to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 July 30, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:43)
- J[ames] Oldham to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 August 1, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:44)
- Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough to Alexander Garrett, re: payment for 7 casks of nails, receipted by John M. Perry and James Guthrie, 1819 Aug 6 1819 August 2, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:45)
- Brockenbrough & Harvie: invoice 1819 August 2-1819 August 16, AD, 1 p. with dockets (Box-folder 1:46)
- Geo[rge] W. Spooner to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 August 9, ALS, 3 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:47)
- Geo[rge] W. Spooner to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 August 13, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:48)
- John M. Perry to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 August 15, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:49)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1728] 1819 August 17, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:50)
- W[illiam B.] Phillips to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 August 20, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:51)
- Geo[rge] W. Spooner to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1819 August 20, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:52)
- S[amuel] J. Harrison to [Thomas Jefferson], endorsed by Thomas Jefferson, originally enclosed with ALS, 1819 August 29, Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, #TB-1731 [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1730] 1819 August 25, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:53)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, originally with enclosure, 1819 August 25 [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1731] 1819 August 29, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:54)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1733] 1819 September 1, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:55)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 September 1, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:56)
- John Hollins to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough with 3 attached receipts 1819 September 3, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:57)
- Valuation of the improvements on land purchased from John M. Perry by Nelson Barksdale (predecessor of Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough ), signed by M.D. Meriwether, et al 1819 September 4, ADS. 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:58)
- John M. Perry to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 September 4, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:59)
- John M. Perry to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [1819 September 4], ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:60)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 September 8, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:61)
- John Bevan to [Thomas Jefferson] 1819 September 10, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:62)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 October 3, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:63)
- James Wade to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 October 7, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:64)
- Tho[ma]s B. Conway to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 October 13, ALS, 1 p. with address (Box-folder 1:65)
- Tho[ma]s B. Conway to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 November 21, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:66)
- Benjamin Collins to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, with proposals for painting 1819 December 1, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:67)
- B[ernard] Peyton to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 December 2, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:68)
- Tho[ma]s B. Conway to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough; receipt on verso 1819 December 13, signed by John Massie 1819 December 8, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:69)
- W[illiam] Roberts to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 December 22, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:70)
- P. A. Sabbaton to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 December 24, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:71)
- W[illia]m Roberts to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1819 December 31, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:72)
- Survey of college lands c. 1819, AD, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:73)
- Table of construction costs by [Thomas Jefferson] [original in Jefferson Papers, #TB-1762] c. 1819, AD, 1:00 PM. (Box-folder 1:74)
- [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough]: Construction estimate; endorsed by Thomas Jefferson [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1758] 1819, AD, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:75)
- [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough]: Memorandum re: plastering prices; endorsed by Thomas Jefferson [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1759] 1819, AD, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:76)
- [Thomas Jefferson] and [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough]: Memoranda on the Raggi brothers. 2 items: calculation of wages by [T.J.], 1 p. with docket; bill of wages, signed by Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, 1 p. with docket [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1763] 1819-1820, AD,. (Box-folder 1:77)
- Miscellaneous accounts 1819, ANS. 81 items. (Box-folder 1:78)
- Miscellaneous receipts 1819, ANS. 51 items. (Box-folder 1:79)
- Estimate of the cost of stonework [by Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough ] 1820 January 1, AD, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:80)
- Thomas Jefferson to Alexander Garrett, with receipt dated 1820 February 13, signed by Thomas Jefferson [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1766] 1820 January 24, ALS, 2 p. with address (Box-folder 1:81)
- Deed of land from John M. Perry and Frances T. Perry to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough (as agent for the University) 1820 January 25, AD (copy). 4 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:82)
- P. A. Sabbaton to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1820 February 20, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:83)
- Jos[eph] P. Sandidge to Nelson Barksdale 1820 February 24, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:84)
- P. A. Sabbaton to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1820 March 9, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:85)
- James Glasgow to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 March 18, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:86)
- Joseph Antrim: proposal for plastering 1820 March 21, AD (copy). 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:87)
- Joseph Antrim: contract for plastering 1820 March 22, AD (copy). 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:88)
- B[ernard] Peyton to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 March 27, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:89)
- John Hollins to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 April 14, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:90)
- Account of University with James Leitch 1820 April 25-1820 November 21, ADS. 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:91)
- D. W. & C. Warwick to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 April 25, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:92)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough - Board of Visitors resolution [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1789] [1820 April], ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:93)
- Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough to [Thomas Jefferson] - [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1790] 1820 May 1, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:94)
- Joseph Antrim to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 May 14, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:95)
- Luther M. George to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 May 16, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:96)
- Brockenbrough & Harvie to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, attached to John Van Lew & Co. account, 1819 August 9-1820 April 10 1820 May 22, ALS, 3 p. with address, dockets (Box-folder 1:97)
- Luther M. George to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 May 22, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:98)
- Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough to John H. Wood (receipted on verso by John H. Wood, 1820 December 4) 1820 May 28, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:99)
- Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough to Thomas Jefferson [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1794] 1820 June 7, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:100)
- Edw[ard] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 June 8, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:101)
- Thomas Perkins to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 June 12, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:102)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 June 14, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:103)
- John Van Lew & Co. to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1820 July 1, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:104)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 July 21, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:105)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough (with account 1819 August 9-1820 July 20) 1820 July 27, ADS/ALS, 3 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:106)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 August 7, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:107)
- W. Bootwright to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 September 6, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:108)
- Thomas Jefferson and John H[artwell] Cocke to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1807] 1820 September 7, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:109)
- W. Bootwright to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 September 29, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:110)
- Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough to [Thomas Jefferson]; endorsed by Thomas Jefferson [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1815] 1820 October 19, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:111)
- Thomas Cooper, M.D. to Alexander Garrett; endorsed by Thomas Jefferson 1820 October 20, ALS, 1 p. with dockets (Box-folder 1:112)
- Robert Moses to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 October 26, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:113)
- Edw[ard] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1820 November 4, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:114)
- Thomas Cooper to Alexander Garrett [1820 November 18], ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 1:115)
- James Harrison: contract as overseer [1820], ADS. 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 1:116)
- Miscellaneous receipts 1820, ANS. 193 items. (Box-folder 1:117)
- Sam[ue]l Cary to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 1, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:118)
- John Nunn to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 2, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:119)
- Agreement between Curtis Carter and John M. Perry 1821 January 4, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:120)
- W[illia]m B. Phillips to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 6, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:121)
- Ch[arle]s Everett to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 7, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:122)
- Dan[ie]l Warwick to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 9, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:123)
- Brockenbrough & Harvie to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 14, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:124)
- E[dward] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 January 18, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:125)
- Dabney Cosby to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 February 8, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:126)
- Edw[ard] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 2, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:127)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 5, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:128)
- Dabney Minor to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough (with enclosure 1821 January 1, R[obert] Crutchfield to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough ) 1821 March 18, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:129)
- Account of the University with Brockenbrough & Harvie 1821 March 22, AD, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:130)
- John Van Lew & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough (with account from 1820 July 20-1821 March 22) 1821 March 22, ALS, 3 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:131)
- D. W. & C. Warwick to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 22, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:132)
- D. W. & C. Warwick to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 23, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:133)
- W[illia]m Dawson & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 24, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:134)
- James Glasgow to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 24, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:135)
- [M.W.] Maury to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 25, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:136)
- Thomas Pickering to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 25, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:137)
- John Carter to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 26, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:138)
- Rich[ar]d Ware to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 27, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:139)
- Thomas Jefferson to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough, with estimate of cost of stonework on verso [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1852] 1821 March 28, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:140)
- Geo[rge] W. Spooner to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 28, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:141)
- Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough to [Thomas Jefferson]; endorsed by Thomas Jefferson [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1854] 1821 March 29, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:142)
- E[dward] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 29, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:143)
- W[illiam] B. Phillips to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 29, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:144)
- Tho[ma]s R. Blackburn to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 30, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:145)
- Malcom F. Crawford to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 30, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:146)
- Ja[me]s Dinsmore to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 30, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:147)
- John M. Perry to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 30, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:148)
- Joseph Pitt to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 30, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:149)
- Dabney Cosby to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 31, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:150)
- James Starke to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 March 31, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:151)
- James W. Widderfield to Thomas Jefferson (with endorsement by Thomas Jefferson) [original in Jefferson Papers #TB-1859] 1821 April 1, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:152)
- Dabney Cosby to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 2, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:153)
- J[ames] Oldham to Board of Visitors 1821 April 2, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:154)
- Geo[rge] W. Spooner to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 3, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:155)
- James W. Widderfield to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 3, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:156)
- John Van Lew & Co. to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1821 April 10, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:157)
- Carter B. Page to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1821 April 11, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:158)
- W[illia]m Roberts to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 11, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:159)
- And[re]w Smith to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1821 April 16, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:160)
- John Van Lew & Co. to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1821 April 17, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:161)
- Tho[mas] Brockenbrough to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 19, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:162)
- Authorization to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough of payment to James Monroe, signed by Ja[me]s Dinsmore, with account: University of Virginia to James Monroe, 1820 October - 1821 April 1821 April 21, ADS. 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:163)
- B[ernard] Peyton to Alexander Garrett, with invoice 1821 April 23, ALS, 2 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:164)
- W[illiam] Thackara and Edw[ar]d Evans to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 23, ALS, 1 p. with address, docket (Box-folder 2:165)
- E[dward] Anderson to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1821 April 24, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:166)
- D. W. & C. Warwick to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 26, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:167)
- E[dward] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 April 28, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:168)
- And[re]w Smith to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 1, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:169)
- James Booker to [Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough] 1821 May 8, ALS, 2 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:170)
- Blackford, Arthur & Co. to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 14, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:171)
- W[illiam] and David Kyle to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 17, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:172)
- E[dward] Lowber to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 19, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:173)
- Carter B. Page to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 22, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:174)
- Tho[mas] Brockenbrough to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 24, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:175)
- And[re]w Smith to Arthur Spicer Brockenbrough 1821 May 30, ALS, 1 p. with docket (Box-folder 2:176)